

calulate statistics on images represent the result

Abstract :
this is a Matlab program to extract data from images that represent the student's grades, its use two mechanisms to solve this problem, first how to extract handwritten Arabic numbers
that represent the student's grade, to solve this problem I used pre-exist neural network I found it on the internet, the second problem is to make the images in a good form for the neural network and write functions for the statistical operations required 

How it work?

1-in "pre-NN and statistics" folder open ocrrecog.m and excute the first part to get the image that is the input to the NN

2-in "Arabic-Handwriting-Recognition-Using-Matlab-master" folder open main.m and run it , then load the image (I DIDNOT WRITE THIS FUNCTIONS I JUST USED THEM YOU CAN    FIND IT HERE
"https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aX92H8pcjfg&t=3s" )

3- excute the rest of ocrrecog.m 



the NN is already trained on pictures on that path
"Arabic-Handwriting-Recognition-Using-Matlab-master\Dictionary\New folder"

 


